<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Paula Andrea</title>
    <link>/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Paula Andrea</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-au</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/project/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>R Ladies Global</title>
      <link>/project/rladies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/rladies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;R-Ladies is a world-wide organization to promote gender diversity in the R community.
I am happy to support this innitiative and I will attend the R ladies meetups in Brussels.
If you live in Ghent and you are intersted in shaping the R ladies community here, please get in contact.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tidyverse workshops</title>
      <link>/project/tidyverse-workshops/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/tidyverse-workshops/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As scientists we deal with experiments to test our hypotheses. These experiments more often are filling our computers and minds with data. Data can give us
answers to our hypotheses, but most of the time we come up with more questions. Here is when, we, as scientists start to realize we are much in need of data analysis skills. The scholar pathway of life scientists is sliding towards data science, by default.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are from a biological science background (or other than engineering) and you are being confronted with the need of computational literacy, you are not
the only one. A good read and advice is here: &lt;a href=&#34;http://journals.plos.org/ploscompbiol/article?id=10.1371/journal.pcbi.1005871&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Ten simple rules for biologists learning to program&lt;/a&gt;. This text also applies to other non-biology fields of
research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why do I give training in data skills?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am currently part of the Training Platform of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.elixir-europe.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Elixir-Europe&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.elixir-belgium.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Elixir-Belgium&lt;/a&gt; as data science and bioinformatics trainer. My career interests include training, R, data analysis, and statistics. My goal as trainer is to help people make data and information &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/sdata201618.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;FAIR&lt;/a&gt;. As a carpentry
instructor and trainer I see the need of supporting data skill needs and leading best practices to work with and manage data.  Hence, that is why I do this job.
As an R enthusiast and open-access advocate I promote R, its community and its resources. R is a tool, as there are many others. The goal of my trainings is not to learn/teach a tool, the goal should be to discover possibilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By experience, I had discovered the multiple possibilities given by the programming language R, its interface Rstudio and many of its packages for specific analyses. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tidyverse.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Tidyverse&lt;/a&gt; is a powerful resource, that is gaining a lot of popularity because of its usefulness and because it is an open door for data science. All of the packages in the tidyverse share a philosophy and interact
well with each other. The best way to start learning the tidyverse is by using
it. I am offering workshops at different levels, and I am happy to have a chat if you have questions or request of workshops. Co-organising workshops with Elixir Belgium is also of my interest. So, contact me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Workhops&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Handle your data the tidy way: an introduction to data science using R and some
of the  packages&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tidyverse packages are intended to make data analysis tasks more efficient. It gives a clear and readable structure to your analysis, resulting in reproducible work products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this workshop you will learn:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The difference between &lt;a href=&#34;http://tidyr.tidyverse.org/articles/tidy-data.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;tidy&lt;/a&gt; and untidy data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to create &lt;a href=&#34;http://tidyr.tidyverse.org/articles/tidy-data.html#sec:tidying&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;tidy&lt;/a&gt; datasets and manipulate them using the main &lt;a href=&#34;http://tidyr.tidyverse.org/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;tidyr&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://dplyr.tidyverse.org/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;dplyr&lt;/a&gt; verbs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make your results reproducible by using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rstudio.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Rstudio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integrate data visualization into your workflow using &lt;a href=&#34;http://ggplot2.tidyverse.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ggplot2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use tidyverse functions to research biological problems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LEVEL&lt;/strong&gt;: A basic knowledge of the R programming language is expected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are hands-on sessions. Atteendees are required to bring their own laptops with the latest versions of R, RStudio and tidyverse installed, instructions
will be given to participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Registration&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vib.be/en/training/research-training/courses/Pages/Elixir-tidyverse-Intro-Feb2018-Antwerp.aspx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Introduction to tidyverse (Antwerpen) Feb 21st, 2018&lt;/a&gt; Instructors: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/SWittouck&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Stijn Wittouck&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/swuyts&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Sander Wuyts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vib.be/en/training/research-training/courses/Pages/Elixir-tidyverse-Intro-March2018-Leuven.aspx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Introduction to tidyverse (Leuven) March 5th&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vib.be/en/training/research-training/courses/Pages/Elixir-tidyverse-Intro-March2018-Ghent.aspx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Introduction to tidyverse (Ghent) March 7th&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to find more events?
&lt;a href=&#34;https://tess.elixir-europe.org/events&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;TeSS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Would you like to be involved in future workshops?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;If there is an offer for a free workshop on data skills, who would like to join? &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/UAntwerpen?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@UAntwerpen&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ugent?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@ugent&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/KU_Leuven?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@KU_Leuven&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/uni_vub?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@uni_vub&lt;/a&gt; would any offer a seminar room? What would be the workshop level? &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ELIXIRnodeBE?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@ELIXIRnodeBE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Paula Andrea (@orchid00) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/orchid00/status/942509173287411713?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;December 17, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please contact &lt;a href=&#34;../../#contact&#34;&gt;me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Train the Trainer</title>
      <link>/project/train-the-trainer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/train-the-trainer/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Translating</title>
      <link>/project/translation-carpentries-lessons/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/translation-carpentries-lessons/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;at-a-glance&#34;&gt;At a glance&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Translating &lt;a href=&#34;https://software-carpentry.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Software carpentry&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://datacarpentry.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Data carpentry&lt;/a&gt; open Access lesson material into Spanish&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contact lead: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/orchid00&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;@orchid00&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;../../#contact&#34;&gt;contact&lt;/a&gt; me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Issue area: #OpenAccess, #OpenData, #OpenEducation, #OpenResearch&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Region: #LatinAmerica_and_Caribbean&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Types of Support Needed: #Coding, #Communications, #Community_Grassroots, #Organizing, #Research, #Translation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Project Website: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Carpentries-ES&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://github.com/Carpentries-ES&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any bilinguals (English-Spanish)? this is your cup of tea and you can help a great project!
I&amp;rsquo;m a volunteer at the Carpentries &lt;a href=&#34;https://software-carpentry.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Software carpentry&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://datacarpentry.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Data carpentry&lt;/a&gt; our goal is to teach researchers basic programming skills to be able to do their research more efficiently. These two are non for profit organisations, which you are more than welcome to join. Recently, we had an open call &lt;a href=&#34;https://software-carpentry.org/blog/2017/09/latin-am-lessons.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://software-carpentry.org/blog/2017/09/latin-am-lessons.html&lt;/a&gt; to grow our community in LatinAmerica. One of the goals is to translate and maintain versions of each lesson in Spanish! As an Open Access, Open Education and Open research project. This is to show that many researchers in Latin America will benefit from these lessons translated, and all your work will be mentioned as contributors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What kinds of support do we need?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Review the already translated lessons (Git and shell, R-gapminder).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work with translating other available lessons.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We also need maintainers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do you need?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this project, people should have fluent English and Spanish skills.
We also need your motivation to learn, or if you are already a Git Master, we need you too!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
